Life, death and something in between.
The Invisible is a fantasy, thriller, mystery film directed by David S. Goyer.
After an attack leaves him in limbo -- invisible to the living and also near death -- a
teenager discovers the only person who might be able help him is his attacker.
Nick Powell, played by Justin Chatwin.
Annie Newton, played by Margarita Levieva.
Diane Powell, played by Marcia Gay Harden.
Marcus Bohem, played by Alex O'Loughlin.
Detective Kate Tunney, played by Michelle Harrison.
Matty, played by Ryan Kennedy.
The Invisible is a 2007 teen supernatural thriller directed by David S.
Goyer and based on the Swedish young adult novel by Mats Wahl.
The film stars Justin Chatwin, Margarita Levieva, Chris
Marquette, Marcia Gay Harden, and Callum Keith Rennie.
It follows a high school student (Chatwin) who is attacked and left for dead, only to find himself trapped
in a liminal state between life and death as he tries to solve his own attempted murder.
The film is a remake of the Swedish film of the same name released in 2002.
This marked the first Hollywood adaptation of a Swedish feature since Intermezzo (1936) and
is cited as starting the modern wave of American remakes of Swedish films.
The American version was released in the United States on April 27, 2007, and was the final
film produced by Hollywood Pictures before the company's closure later that year.
The film explores themes of high school, remake,
out of body experience, school life.
The tone is mind_bending and intense.